Privacy Policy
==============

Last updated on October 30th, 2022

Summary

We hope you read this entire Privacy Policy. However, if you're in a hurry, here is a brief overview of the most important points:

* Information that we collect from you is limited to your Roblox User ID and your Discord ID (if you provide it to us), and Experience time played data for users with Experience playtime logging features enabled. Paid subscribers billing information is collected by our payment partner, Paddle. For information on how Paddle handles your user data please visit: [https://paddle.com/privacy/](https://paddle.com/privacy/)
* We do not and will not sell your information.
* We use our own cookies to provide and protect our product. We do not collect any cookies from Roblox.
* You can exercise your GDPR and CCPA rights. For users in jurisdictions where these rules apply (European Union, European Economic Area, or California), please [contact us](https://ropro.io/support) to exercise any of the enumerated rights.
* If you have any questions or concerns about this policy, you can [contact us](https://ropro.io/support).

What is the scope of this Privacy Policy?
-----------------------------------------

This Privacy Policy is incorporated into RoPro's Terms of Service and License Agreement, located at [https://ropro.io/terms](https://ropro.io/terms), and applies to the information obtained by us through your use of RoPro's Site, Software, and Services as described in this Policy.

Information collection and use
------------------------------

### Information you provide us when you use RoPro

When you utilize our Services, you voluntarily give us certain Personal Data, including:

* Your Roblox User ID, Discord ID (if you provide it to us), Experience time played data for users with Experience playtime logging features enabled.
* Your payment information, if you are a paying customer is collected and handled by our payment partner and merchant of record, Paddle. For information on how Paddle handles your payment information please visit: [https://paddle.com/privacy/](https://paddle.com/privacy/)

* We **do not** collect or use your Roblox cookies or any other personal information regarding your Roblox account.

### Other Information we collect

We collect this information as you use the RoPro service

* _User Content._ This consists of text or other content entered by you in connection with your use of RoPro. This includes RoPro Comments, RoPro Trade Offers, and other RoPro add-ons that require user content to be entered.

### Information collected from other sources

* We may collect anonymized user data via third-party marketing and analytics tools such as Google Analytics on our website ropro.io. This data is not personalized to you and is solely for the purpose of understanding our user base and growth metrics.

How does RoPro use my Information?
----------------------------------

* To help us provide and administer our Site, Software, and/or Services, authenticate users for security purposes, provide personalized user features and access, process transactions, conduct research, develop new features, and improve the features, algorithms, and usability of our Site, Software, and/or Services.
* To communicate with you about your use of our Site, Software, and/or Services, product announcements, and software updates, as well as respond to your requests for assistance, including providing account verification support if you're having difficulty accessing your account.
* To display User Content associated with your account and make sure it is available to you when you use our Services.
* To calculate aggregate statistics on the number of unique devices using our Site, Software, and/or Services, and to detect and prevent fraud and misuse of those.
* To improve our services, when provided publicly. For example, we may use game time data which has been toggled to public for the purpose of improving recommendations.

Does RoPro review User Content?
-------------------------------

* Public user content submitted via RoPro, such as RoPro Comments or RoPro Trade Offers is initially automatically reviewed to ensure that it is appropriate, and can be subject to manual review and moderation. Non-public User Content such as RoPro Outfit names are not subject to review, but may be viewed if we believe the Terms of Service have been violated and confirmation is required, if we need to do so to respond to your requests for support, or if we otherwise determine that we have an obligation to review it as described in the Terms of Service.

Information access and disclosure
---------------------------------

### Does RoPro share my Information?

We only disclose Personal Data to third parties when…

* …we use service providers who assist us in meeting business operations needs, including hosting, delivering, and improving our Services. We also use service providers for specific services and functions, including email communication, customer support services, and analytics. These service providers may only access, process, or store Personal Data pursuant to our instructions and to perform their duties to us.
* Examples of this include: Google Analytics (analytics), Zendesk (support), or Paddle (payment processing).
* …we believe it is necessary to investigate potential violations of the Terms of Service, to enforce those Terms of Service, or to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, or potential threats against persons, property, or the systems on which we operate our Site, Software, and/or Services.

RoPro does not share your Personal Data with third parties for the purpose of enabling them to deliver their advertisements to you.

### Does RoPro sell or rent my Personal Data?

No, RoPro does not sell or rent your Personal Data.

### Does RoPro use cookies?

Cookies are small text files stored on your device and used by web browsers to deliver personalized content and remember logins and account settings. RoPro uses cookies to collect usage and analytic data that helps us provide our Site, Software, and/or Services to you, as well as to create unique sessions between you and our Service for the purpose of providing personalized features, managing settings, and managing subscriptions. We do not use cookies for the purposes of advertising our product or any other product to you. We do not use or store third party cookies such as Roblox cookies with the exception of Google Analytics cookies which track anonymized usage of our Site and Service.

### Will RoPro send me emails?

We do not collect emails from non-paid users. For paid subscribers, from time to time, we may want to contact you with information about product announcements or software updates. You may opt out of such communications at any time by clicking the “unsubscribe” link found within RoPro emails. Our payment partner, Paddle, will also send emails to paid users regarding their subscription status, including recently purchased subscription keys or overdue payment reminders. We will not sell your email address, or spam your email address with product offers.

Does RoPro ever make any of my Personal Data or User Content public?
--------------------------------------------------------------------

Personal Data or User Content is only made public when it is provided to us for the express purpose of being public. An example of this is when you use the "Link Discord to Profile" feature, or when you post a RoPro Comment or RoPro Trade Offer. At no point will any privately provided Personal Data such as your email address be made public.

### Does RoPro collect information from children?

RoPro does not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13. It is for this reason that several of our features (such as linking Discord account to profile) are disabled for <13 Roblox users. If we determine we have collected personal information from a child younger than 13 years of age, we will take reasonable measures to remove that information from our systems. If you are under the age of 13, please do not submit any personal information through the Site, Service, and/or Software. We encourage parents and legal guardians to monitor their children's internet usage and to help enforce this Policy by instructing their children never to provide personal information through the Site, Service, and/or Software without their permission.

Data storage, transfer, retention, and deletion
-----------------------------------------------

### Where is my Information stored?

Information submitted to RoPro will be transferred to, processed, and stored in the United States. When you use the Software on your computing device, User Content you save will be stored locally on that device and synced with our servers. If you post or transfer any Information to or through our Site, Software, and/or Services, you are agreeing to such Information, including Personal Data and User Content, being hosted and accessed in the United States. Please note that the laws of the United States may be different from the privacy laws applicable to the place where you are resident.

### How secure is my Information?

RoPro is committed to protecting the security of your Information and takes reasonable precautions to protect it. However, internet data transmissions, whether wired or wireless, cannot be guaranteed to be 100% secure, and as a result, we cannot ensure the security of Information you transmit to us, including Personal Data and User Content; accordingly, you acknowledge that you do so at your own risk.  
  
We use industry-standard encryption to protect your data in transit and at rest. All data sent to and from RoPro is encrypted via the HTTPS protocol.  
  
Once we receive your data, we protect it on our servers using a combination of technical, physical, and logical security safeguards. The security of the data stored locally in any of our Software installed on your computing device requires that you make use of the security features of your device. We recommend that you take the appropriate steps to secure all computing devices that you use in connection with our Site, Software, and Services.  
  
If RoPro learns of a security system breach, we may attempt to notify you and provide information on protective steps, if available, through the email address that you have provided to us or by posting a notice on the Site. Depending on where you live, you may have a legal right to receive such notices in writing.  
  
It is important to keep in mind, though, that RoPro does not store private information such as passwords. The most private information we may keep on you is your email address, which is stored securely on our server.

### How can I delete my personal data from RoPro?

If you would like to remove any personal data that has been collected by RoPro, please contact us via our support chat: [https://ropro.io/support](https://ropro.io/support).

Will this Privacy Policy ever change?
-------------------------------------

As RoPro evolves, we may need to update this Policy to keep pace with changes in our Site, Software, and Services, our business, and laws applicable to us and you. We will, however, always maintain our commitment to respect your privacy. We will notify you of any material changes that impact your rights under this Policy by email (to your most recently provided email address) or post any other revisions to this Policy, along with their effective date, in an easy-to-find area of the Site, so we recommend that you periodically check back here to stay informed of any changes. Please note that your continued use of RoPro after any change means that you agree with and consent to be bound by the new Policy. If you disagree with any changes in this Policy and do not wish your information to be subject to it, you will need to stop use of our Site and/or Services. You can always contact us to remove any personal data as described above.

Exercising GDPR or CCPA privacy rights
--------------------------------------

You can exercise your GDPR or CCPA rights. For users in jurisdictions where these rules apply (European Union, European Economic Area, or California), please [contact us](https://ropro.io/support) to exercise any of the rights enumerated under these statutes.
